尼拿克 拿辣酱来
Nick Nack, Tabasco !
立刻送来 斯卡曼加先生
Right away, Monsieur Scaramanga.
等等
Hey.
只是一半
Half.
其余的待会给你
You get the rest later.
在里面等他 从那道门进去
Wait for him in there, through that door.
他很快就跟你会合
He will join you in a minute.
斯卡曼加先生 蒸汽浴已准备好
Your steam bath is ready, Monsieur Scaramanga.
噢!
Oh!
那样太没难度了
That would have been too easy.
它是锁上的
It's locked.
你要到别处找 先生
You'll have to look elsewhere, monsieur.
艾尔
Hey, AI . AI .
不管你在哪里 别用枪指着我
Wherever you are, don't hold it against me.
斯卡曼加先生 我不知你在哪里 可以找到你的枪
I wonder where you can find your gun , Monsieur Scaramanga.
你那小金枪
Your little golden gun.
会在哪儿呢?
Where can it be?
有些是我们以前没有试过的
There is something we haven't had before.
我在想那会是什么
I wonder what it can be.
我耍你的!
I fooled you.
你越来越接近了
You're getting warmer.
很接近了
Much warmer.
现在你如何下楼梯?
Now, how are you going to get down the stairs?
你是这么接近 然而又那么远
So near and yet so far.
了不起 斯卡曼加先生
Bravo, Monsieur Scaramanga.
你又成功了
You've done it again .
那是最好的 是吗?
This one was the best, n'est-ce pas?
十分不错
Not bad . Not bad at all .
如果想要我的钱
But you'll have to do better than that
就得有更好表现
if you want to come into my money.
我会做到的 我会享用你留给我的每一分钱
I'll get you yet, and I'll enjoy every sou you leave me.
你快累死我了 尼拿克
You'll be the death of me yet, Nick Nack.
《007系列之金枪人》
长官 早安
Good morning , sir.
科尔索普
Colthorpe.
参谋长
Chief of Staff.
007 你认识一个叫 斯卡曼加的家伙吗?
What do you know about a man called Scaramanga, 007?
斯卡曼加?
Scaramanga?
你指那个拥有金手枪的人
Oh , yes. The Man with the Golden Gun .
在马戏班出生 父亲是 马戏演出指挥 大概是古巴人
Born in a circus. Father, the ringmaster, possibIy Cuban .
母亲是英国人 玩蛇的
Mother, English , a snake charmer.
他十岁时已精通花式射击
He was a spectacular trick shot artist by the time he was 10...
十五岁就在里约当上枪手
and a local Rio gunman at 15.
苏联国安会招揽他 让他在欧洲受训
The KGB recruited him there and trained him in Europe
在那儿 他成为一个付出多 但报酬少的杀手
where he became an overworked , underpaid assassin .
在五十年代末期他自立门户
He went independent in the late '50s.
每次行动收取一百万元
Current price, $ 1 million a hit.
档案里没有他的相片
No photograph on file.
不过他有一个很显著的特征
But he does have one distinguishing feature, however,
一个额外乳头
a superfluous papilla.
什么?
A what?
是乳腺
A mammary gland .
第三个乳头
A third nipple, sir.
他经常使用金枪弹 所以外号是"金枪人"
He always uses a golden bullet, hence, Man with the Golden Gun .
目前居所不详
Present domicile unknown .
这就是我所知的
I think that's all .
为什么这样问?
Why, sir?
嗯
Hmm .
有趣的小装饰
Charming trinket.
还有我的号码
Even has my number on it.
的确
Precisely.
很明显 这子弹根本没用
Obviously it's useless as a bullet.
谁会付上一百万要我的性命?
I mean , sir, who would pay a million dollars to have me killed?
妒忌的丈夫、愤怒的厨子 受侮辱的裁缝
Jealous husbands, outraged chefs, humiliated tailors.
可以说不完 而且这个小装饰
The list is endless.
还附上一张便条
Moreover, this trinket, as you call it,
要求特别呈递给你
was sent with a note requesting special delivery to you .
署名是一个"S"字母
It's initialed with an "S."
上面的指纹已给中情局
Scaramanga's fingerprints were on it.
证实是属于斯卡曼加的
They've been verified by the CIA.
他为何要警告我?
Why would he alert me?
心理因素
Psychological .
他想倚重自己的名声 吓怕他的受害人
He counts on his reputation to terrify his intended victim .
谢谢你们
Thank you , gentlemen .
我会把你撤离目前的任务
I'm relieving you of your present assignment, 007.
- 长官 - 什么?
- Sir? - Yes?
能源危机仍然没解决
The energy crisis is still with us.
我完全认同找出吉勃逊
I respectfully submit that finding Gibson
和他的太阳电池数据 是现在最重要的事
and his solar cell data is even more important than ever.
的确是
It is indeed .
而我不能祸及此事和其他任务
And I can't jeopardize it or any mission
全因为斯卡曼加突然出现射杀你
by having Scaramanga pop up and put a bullet in you .
我会批准你辞职的要求
I'll endorse your request to resign .
或者你可以休假躲起来
Or you can take a sabbatical and
直到事情解决为止
go to ground until this matter's settled .
或者直到他把我杀死为止
Or until he kills me.
没有人知道他在哪里 或者他是什么模样
Nobody knows where he is or what he looks like.
所以说他比你有优势是没错的
So I think it's fair to assume that he has the edge on you .
你同意吗? 没什么事了
Wouldn't you agree? That's all , 007.
如果我先找到他
If I found him first, sir,
形势或会有变
that might change the situation .
戏剧性地变化
Dramatically.
不是吗?
Wouldn't you say?
再见 邦德
Good day, Bond .
钱班霓费尔班克斯
Moneypenny, Fairbanks. . .
阿拉斯加?
AIaska?
不 是002比尔费尔班克斯
No, Bill Fairbanks, 002.
可怜的比尔 我怀念他
Oh , poor Bill . I miss him .
那个金枪人却不会
The Man with the Golden Gun didn't.
从没正式确定是他做的
Officially, that was never confirmed .
事发时002在哪里?
Where was 002 when it happened?
当年1969年 在贝鲁特
Beirut, '69.
他跟一名叫萨达的女子 在夜总会内
In a cabaret with a lady called Saida.
贝鲁特?
Beirut, hmm?
你比电脑还要出色
Moneypenny, you are better than a computer.
在各方面都是的
In all sorts of ways.
不过你从没好好利用它
But you never take advantage of them .
- 钱班霓小姐?  - 是的 长官
- Miss Moneypenny. - Yes, sir.
等一下 亲爱的
Oh , just one moment, darling .
什么事 詹姆斯?
Yes, James?
为何不确定凶手是斯卡曼加?
Why wasn't Scaramanga confirmed as the killer?
因为他们找不到子弹
Because they couldn't find the bullet,
亲爱的
darling .
亚默
Ahmed .
晚安 我叫做邦德
Good evening . My name is Bond .
詹姆斯邦德
James Bond .
你跳得非常好
Your dancing is superb.
你也是
So are you .
而且你很帅
And you are very handsome.
我很少会这样唐突的 但我
Well , I don't usually intrude like this, but I . . .
我相信我们有一个共同朋友
I believe we had a mutual friend .
比尔费尔班克斯
Bill Fairbanks.
费尔班克斯?
Fairbanks?
对
Yes.
听说在他被袭击时
I'm told you were with him
你是跟他一起的
when he was rather rudely interrupted .
没错是比尔 那是个恐怖的晚上
BiII . What a terrible night.
我永不会忘记
I will never forget it.
看到是谁射他的吗?
Did you see who shot him?
不 我在他的怀里
No. I was in his arms.
我闭上了眼
My eyes were closed .
至少他死时快乐
At least he died happy.
那颗子弹直穿过他!
The bullet went through him .
穿过他背脊到那里?
Through his back and ended up there?
不 穿过他脖子
No, no, through his neck.
在警方抵达前 我把子弹从墙上取出
I take it out of the wall before the police arrive.
它现在是我的护身符
And now it is my lucky charm .
没有它我不会跳舞
I never dance without it.
相信比尔会很喜欢
I'm sure Bill wouId have loved that.
让我们忘记过去吧
But let us forget the past.
嗯
Hmm .
我一直希望你这样说
I was hoping you'd say that.
你会在贝鲁特久留吗?
Are you staying long in Beirut?
视乎情况吧
It depends.
我真笨拙
Clumsy of me.
你的小腹真美
You really do have a magnificent abdomen .
我的香水! 不!
Oh , my perfumes ! No !
我的护身符不见了!
I've lost my charm !
我不这么认为
Not from where I'm standing .
计程车 要去饭店吗?
Taxi? Hotel , mister?
不 到最近的药房去
No. The nearest pharmacy.
这种改制过的子弹 在撞击时变得偏平
Dumdum bullets like this flatten on impact
以求达到最高的杀伤力
for maximum wounding effect.
很厉害
Very nasty.
相信也是
Yes. I'm sure it is.
它是在哪里和由谁制造的?
But just tell me where it was made and by whom .
幸好它仍完整
FortunateIy it's all in one piece.
20点003克
20. 003 grams.
我们推断 它应该由一支 4点2公厘口径的枪射出
Which leads us to deduce it was fired from a 4.2 millimeter gun .
根本没有4点2公厘口径的枪
Colthorpe, there's no such thing as a 4.2 millimeter gun .
即使没有军事 或民事的军火制造商
The fact that no recognized munitions manufacturer,
制造这样的子弹
military or civil , produces such a bullet
并不代表它不存在
doesn't mean it doesn't exist, 007.
"Q"也有为特别的目的
Q Branch have been making irreguIar calibers
而制造特别口径的手枪
for most unusual purposes.
而我们也没把记号或型号刻上
And we don't put markings or serial numbers on them .
所以几乎不能确认
Making identification almost impossible.
没办法追寻那子弹的来源?
You mean to say there's no way to trace that bullet?
你不知道它怎样来到这里
You have no idea what it went through to get here.
我不会详细覆述
I wouldn't go so far as to say that.
以我们的标准来说
The workmanship is undemanding
它的手工不算精细
according to our standards.
23开纯金混以少量镍
Soft 23 karat gold with traces of nickel .
欧洲很少使用 是来自印度的
Hardly ever used in Europe. Comes from India.
远东?
The Far East?
为何不可是印度?
Why not India?
镍含量明显很少
Nickel content obviously too low, 007.
拉萨?
Lazar?
嗯
Hmm .
充满幻想力 很专业
Imaginative. Highly specialized .
对! 我同意
Yes, I concur.
拉萨是什么?
Well , what the hell is Lazar?
不是"什么" 是"谁" 葡萄牙人
Not what. Who. Portuguese.
住在澳门
Lives in Macau .
就是制造那指弹的家伙
Chap who made the bullet, 007.
抱歉打扰你们晚膳
I hate to interrupt your dinner,
拉萨先生住在这儿吗?
but does Senhor Lazar live here?
拉萨
Lazar.
有人给我这个地址
I was given this address.
他是否?  拉萨先生?
Does he. . . Senhor Lazar?
我叫做邦德 詹姆斯邦德
My name's Bond . James Bond .
想不到的荣幸 邦德先生
An unexpected honor, Mr. Bond .
久仰大名
Your reputation precedes you .
请到这边来
This way, please.
若我可以为你制造某东西
It would be the proudest moment of my career
那将是我的荣幸
if I could make something for you , Mr. Bond .
来福枪吗?
A rifle, perhaps?
我们有个很有趣的问题
Now, here we have an interesting problem .
这个是为客人特制的
A custom-built model for a client
他不久前失去了两只手指 请
who recently lost two fingers. Please.
他失去了扳机
He also lost his trigger.
它藏于枪托内 扣压它
It is housed in the butt. Squeeze it.
瞄准器有点偏差
The sights are a bit off.
你有五只手指
You have five fingers.
枪托是供三只手指压力平衡的
The butt is balanced for the pressure of three.
所以你射低了一寸
That is why you were one inch too low.
在这里只有精湛手艺与高质素
Here you will find only craftsmanship and quality.
而那大量生产的
Mass production ,
譬如你的沃尔达PPK 则留给其他人吧
your Walther PPK, for instance, I leave to others.
那么弹药呢?
What about ammunition?
为个人要求而设计 无论要求怎样
Designed to individual requirements whatever they may be.
如果我要用黄金打造呢?
In gold , if I wanted?
我替一个顾客做过了
I have already done that for a client.
我知道
I know you have.
弗朗斯科斯卡曼加
Francisco Scaramanga.
我跟顾客的关系
My relationship with a client, Mr. Bond ,
是绝对保密的
is strictly confidential .
如一个医生 神父跟忏悔者的关系
Like a doctor or priest with a penitent.
当然了
Of course.
但你仍然为没手指的无赖造枪
Yet you make guns for fingerless hoodlums,
为刺客制造子弹
bullets for assassins.
邦德先生 子弹不会杀人的
Mr. Bond , bullets do not kill .
拉扳机的人的手指
It is the finger that pulls the trigger.
没错
Exactly.
我正瞄准你的鼠蹊
I'm now aiming precisely at your groin .
快说 否则你要 永远拿着你那话儿
So speak, or forever hold your "piece."
我从没见过斯卡曼加先生
I have never seen Mr. Scaramanga.
以每颗子弹收费的情形下 他必定是你的最佳顾客
On a cost-per-bullet basis, he must be your best customer.
没错 不过
That is true, but unfortunately
他不是经常开火的
he seems onIy to fire them occasionally.
上一次的送货 是什么时候?
When was the last shipment?
邦德先生 不可能的 我不可
Mr. Bond , this is impossible. I cannot. . .
你说得对
You're quite right.
低了一寸
An inch too low.
我才刚完成一张立刻运送的订单
I have just completed an order for immediate delivery.
谁去收货?
Who collects them?
我发誓不知道
I swear I do not know.
他们叫我送去赌场
My instructions are to go the casino.
我收了钱 他们就消失了
I am paid and they vanish .
几分钟后
In a few momen ts, ladies and gentlemen,
我们就会抵达香港海港
we will be in Hong Kong Harbor,
它是世上最繁忙的港口之一
one of the busiest ports in the world.
请准备你们的护照及登陆证
May I remind you to have your passports and landing cards ready
以避免任何不必要的延误
in order to avoid unnecessary delay.
左手边是著名客轮 伊利沙白皇后号的残骸
On our left is the wreckage of the famous liner, Queen Elizabeth ,
它在1971年在这里神秘沉下
which sank here under mysterious circumstances in 1971 .
前面就是九龙
Ahead, you can now see Kowloon.
右手边就是香港岛
And on your right, Hong Kong Island.
计程车!
Taxi !
跟着那辆劳斯
Follow that Rolls.
小姐 请你把这倒转的 便盆驶开好吗?
Madam , would you be good enough to move this inverted bedpan?
抱歉我迟到 你在澳门的讯息
I'm sorry I'm late, James, but your signal
才刚传到办公室
from Macau only just reached the office.
你真是好帮手 晚安
You're a great help, Goodnight.
去交通部查一下那辆车吧
Now, get on to the license bureau and trace that car.
"AU603"的绿色劳斯
AU603. A green Rolls.
绿色劳斯?
A green Rolls?
绿色劳斯莱斯
A green Rolls-Royce.
香港不会有太多的
There can't be that many in Hong Kong .
所有绿色劳斯莱斯
Courtesy cars.
都是半岛酒店的免费接客车
AII green Rolls-Royces belong to the PeninsuIa Hotel .
看两年的工作
You see what a two-year posting
对情报人员有多大转变?
to Staff Intelligence does for a girl .
詹姆斯 见到你真好
James, it's wonderful to see you .
你要去哪里?
Where are you going?
我需要一些资料
I need some information .
被跟踪的目标人物 住在602号房间
The subject under surveillance is occupying Room 602.
我请你吃晚饭
I'll buy you dinner tonight, Goodnight.
但我先要办些正经事
But first I have a little official business to attend to.
我看到那正经事了
Yes, I saw the official business.
晚安 经过这两年 我会对你那样做吗?
Goodnight, would I do that to you after two years?
会 你一定会!
Yes, you bloody well wouId .
- 让我帮你 - 不用了
- Please. - I can manage.
不过你可替我开门
Oh , you could open a door for me, though .
- 我替你开香槟吧?  - 不 这是惊喜
- I open champagne. - It's a surprise.
是惊喜!
Oh , a surprise !
午安
Good afternoon .
水枪?
A water pistol?
把浴袍拿给我
Pass me that robe.
转身
Turn around .
你经常带手枪沐浴的吗?
Do you always take a shower with a pistol?
举高手 离开这里!
Put your hands up and get out of here !
继续走
Keep on walking .
你还没回答我的问题
But you haven't answered my question .
接待处 有什么可帮你?
Reception. Can I help you?
我是602号房间的安黛拉小姐
This is Miss Anders, Room 602.
把它放下!
Put those down !
我明白这些烟盒上面 为何写上政府忠告
I see why these packets carry a government warning .
还给我!
Give me that!
它的确会危害你的健康
They certainly can damage your health .
你弄疼我的手臂!
You're hurting my arm .
我可扭断它除非你 说出那些子弹的下落
I'll break it unless you tell me where those bullets go.
我不能说!
I can't.
试一试!
Try!
- 他会杀掉我!  - 谁?
- He'll kill me. - Who?
我不能告诉你!
I can't tell you .
斯卡曼加
Scaramanga.
你肯试不就做到了吗?
You see what you can do when you try?
你替他工作?
You work for him?
我不是
I don't work for him .
他是我是他的
He's. . . I'm his. . .
他是你的爱人
Oh , so he's a lover, too.
只是在他杀人之前
Only before he kills.
斗牛勇士也是那样做
Bullfighters do the same thing .
说可以改善目力
Claim it improves the eye.
他要杀我 我可在哪里找到他?
His eye is on me. Where can I find him?
不知道
I don't know.
哪里?
I said where?
我不知道!  他不是什么都告诉我的!
I don't know where. He doesn't tell me everything .
他今晚会在露臀夜总会
I know he has a date at the Bottoms Up Club tonight.
我怎认得出他?
How will I recognize him?
高 瘦 黑
Tall , slim and dark.
那跟我的阿姨一样
So is my aunt.
他有任何特征吗?
Anything distinctive about him?
有 不过我如何
Yes, but how can I . . .
他不像普通人 他有三个
He's not like other people. He has three. . .
哦
Oh .
奇妙的解剖学趣闻
Fascinating anatomical tidbit
这是我所听过最没用处的资料
but probably the most useless piece of information I ever heard .
除非露臀夜总会是 一间脱衣舞厅
Unless of course the Bottoms Up is a strip cIub
而斯卡曼加又在那儿表演
and Scaramanga is performing there.
你要说多一点
You'll have to do better.
他通常穿着白色麻布西装 戴黑色领带
He usually wears a white linen suit, black tie,
首饰全是黄金造的
and jewelry, aII goId .
有进步
You're improving .
我不希望你再扭我的臂
I don't want you to twist my arm again .
我也不希望
I don't want to either.
听着我给你的吩咐
So I'll tell you what you're going to do, Miss Anders.
拿那些金子弹给斯卡曼加先生
You're going to take those golden bullets to Mr. Scaramanga
他拿不到子弹
because if he doesn't get them ,
就不会在露臀夜总会出现
he may not show up at the Bottoms Up.
我在那里看到他
And I want him there.
你为何相信我?
Why should you trust me?
我不相信
I don't.
不过若斯卡曼加听到
But neither will Mr. Scaramanga trust you
我们的对话他也不会相信你
if he hears about this interesting little conversation .
谁晓得?
Who knows?
他或会用一颗金子弹对付你
He may even use one of those little golden bullets on you .
那就太可惜了
And that would be a pity
因为子弹非常贵
because they're very expensive.
我会拿给他
I'll take them to him .
喝一杯吧
Let's drink to that.
干杯?
Bottoms up.
苏打还是姜汁汽水?
Soda or ginger ale?
劳烦你 姜汁汽水
Ginger ale, please.
警察! 把枪放下!  放下
Police ! Drop it! Drop it.
你已被逮捕
You're under arrest.
别走近!
Move away from there !
检查那把枪
If you take the trouble to examine that gun ,
是没开过火的
you'll notice it hasn't been fired .
有任何话要说 到了警局再说
Anything you have to say, you can say at the station .
我以第473条例控告你
I'm charging him under Section 473.
我没看到你的工作证
I didn't see your identity card .
待会就会看到
You will .
不是到警局吗?
Here. I thought we were going to the police station .
到九龙那边
Kowloon side.
九龙在那边!
Kowloon's over there !
我们去新界
We are going to the New Territories.
欢迎 邦德指挥官
Welcome aboard, Commander Bond.
请来这边
This way, sir.
请走到舱口下
Down the hatchway, please.
晚安
Good evening , sir.
请跟我来 好吗?
Would you follow me, pIease?
它肯定给你一个新的倾向吧
Hmm . It certainly gives you a new slant.
附近有中国舰队
What with the Chinese on one side
也有美国舰队
and the American fleet on the other,
香港只有这地方是不会被窃听的
down here's the only place in Hong Kong you can't be bugged .
以香港现在的房地产价格来说
And , with current real estate prices in Hong Kong ,
的确是蛮便宜的
quite practical , really.
有发现吗?
Any luck?
我们打捞到的中国战机
Chinese fighter we managed to salvage.
晚安 007
Good evening , 007.
很高兴你仍与我们一起
Glad to see you're still with us.
如果你将来
In future, Commander Bond , if you must
要去游览绿灯户
tour the world of Suzie Wong by night,
请通知我们的手下 赫副官
kindly inform our man here, Lieutenant Hip.
对不起
Sorry, Commander.
我要你摆脱香港警方
I had to get you away from the Hong Kong police
但又不知道你掌握了多少情况
but didn't know how much you knew.
什么也不知道 但我应报告
Nothing . But I think I should report, sir,
斯卡曼加不是要暗杀我
that Scaramanga does not have a contract on me.
他今晚有机会
He couldn't have missed me tonight.
但他杀了一个家伙
Instead he hit some chap coming out of a club.
看到那是谁后 使我颇惊讶的
I got quite a shock when I saw who it was.
我也料到了
I should think you did .
是我们失踪了的 太阳能源专家吉勃逊
Our missing solar energy expert, Gibson .
没错
Yes, Gibson .
他本来准备在某种情形下回来的
He was prepared to come back under certain conditions.
所以我才与费雷泽教授在这里
That's why I'm out here with Professor Frazier.
赫副官在进行初步接触
Lieutenant Hip was making a preliminary contact.
我真想让斯卡曼加暗杀你
I almost wish that Scaramanga had a contract on you .
吉勃逊合作吗?
Was Gibson cooperative?
他想要求豁免权
He wanted to bargain for immunity.
他提议到曼谷商讨细节
Suggested another meeting in Bangkok to discuss terms.
为何选择曼谷?
Why Bangkok?
他好像在当地为海发办事的
I got the impression he worked there for Hai Fat.
我曾听过这名字
That name's come up before.
是亿万富翁
A multimillionaire.
是海发企业的主管
Head of Hai Fat Enterprises.
据我们所知 全都是合法生意
All of them legitimate as far as we know.
吉勃逊用什么来讲条件?
What did Gibson propose bargaining with , Lieutenant?
太阳能感应器 声称95%有效
A solex. Claimed it was 95% efficient.
若他能发明那样有效能的电池 就能解决能源危机
If he developed a solar cell that efficient, he solved the energy crisis.
你已告诉过我了
So you've told me.
煤和石油迟早会用尽
Coal and oil will soon be depleted .
铀又太危险
Uranium's too dangerous.
地热和潮水控制太昂贵 我很清楚的
Geothermal and tidal control too expensive. I know all that.
太阳能感应器现在在哪?
Where's the solex now?
是太阳能感应震动器
Solex agitator, sir.
那是把太阳光线转变为
The essential unit to convert radiation from the sun into electricity
工业用的电力的重要东西
on an industrial basis.
只有这样大
It's only about that size.
很快就可以知道那是否有效
It won't take me long to check out Gibson's efficiency claim .
真叫人兴奋
This is really exciting .
我可以看看吗?
May I see it, Lieutenant?
他曾在酒吧拿给我看 但又放回口袋里
He showed it to me at the bar and replaced it in his pocket.
而当他被杀后
And after he was shot,
那就不见了
it wasn't there.
我找过
I looked .
恭喜你们
M: Gentlemen , I congratulate you .
还以为可以得到一个 改良了的太阳能感应器
Instead of getting our hands on a perfected solex,
还只得一条没用的尸体 毫无线索
we're left with a useless corpse and no leads.
有一个线索
One lead , sir.
假设吉勃逊被斯卡曼加所杀
Assuming Gibson was killed by Scaramanga,
聘用他的能付上一百万元
whoever hired him could afford a million dollars.
你指海发?
Are you suggesting Hai Fat?
他有这财力
He could afford it.
对他来说是小数目
Out of petty cash .
我刚想到
A thought has just occurred to me, sir.
如果海发聘用斯卡曼加
If Hai Fat hired Scaramanga,
他应该不会亲自跟他见面
it's highly unlikely that he met him personally.
为什么?
Why?
若出了任何状况
In the event of anything going wrong ,
也没什么可把他们连在一起
there's nothing to connect the two.
这让我想到可如何走近他
And that gives me an idea as to how to approach him .
Q 我需要这个
Q, I'll need this.
真的 007!
Really, 007 !
我承认这有点怪异
I admit, it's a little kinky.
你带晚安一起去吧
You'll take Miss Goodnight with you .
晚安?
Goodnight, sir?
经过今晚的失败后
After tonight's debacle,
一个有效率的联络官 是不会有错的
an efficient liaison officer wouldn't come amiss.
谢谢你们
Thank you , sir.
你不可能接近海发的
You won't get anywhere near Hai Fat.
我有亲杯在曼谷
I have some relatives in Bangkok.
我经常经过他的地方
I have often passed his place.
他住在山边一所大屋内 守卫森严
He lives in a big house on a mountainside surrounded by guards.
没办法
No way.
到处都是守卫
The place is crawling with guards.
你来看看
Have a look.
海发很重视私隐的
Hai Fat takes his privacy very seriously.
我肯定他会见我
I'm sure he'll see me.
早安 水怎样?
Good morning . How's the water?
为何你不下水看看?
Why don't you come in and find out?
似乎很吸引 小姐是
Sounds very tempting , Miss. . .
赵美
Chew Mee.
真的?
Really?
只有一个麻烦
Well , there's only one small problem .
我没有游泳裤
I have no swimming trunks.
我也没有
Neither have I .
你在做什么?
HAI FAT: What are you doing here?
滚!
Get out.
立刻滚!
Immediately.
我要把你
I will have you . . .
请原谅 斯卡曼加先生
Please, forgive me, Mr. Scaramanga.
再见 赵美
Excuse me, Chew Mee.
再见
Bye.
你了解到我的惊讶吧
You understand my surprise.
我以为大家了解
I thought it was understood .
我们不见面 斯卡曼加先生
We were never to meet, Mr. Scaramanga.
我总以为你的特征只是个传说
I always thought your abnormality was a myth .
有些邪教相信 这是刀枪不入
There are cults where it is considered a sign of invulnerability
和高超的性能力
and great sexual prowess.
我已经习惯了它
I've learned to live with it.
你为何在这里?
Why are you here?
因为詹姆斯邦德
Bond . James Bond .
我认识这个人吗?
Do I know the gentleman?
他认识你
Well , he knows you .
恕我大胆地说
Without being immodest,
在世界这一端没有人不认识他
there's hardly anyone in this part of the world who doesn't.
只有很少人没听过邦德的名字
And there are very few people who haven't heard of Bond .
英国特务情报员007有特权杀人
British Secret Service, 007, licensed to kill .
即使以我的标准来说 他非常好
He's good , even by my standards.
他到过露臀夜总会附近
He was near the Bottoms Up Club.
只是巧合
A coincidence.
我不相信他们
I don't believe in them .
这家伙很危险 他知道一些事情
The man's a menace. He knows something .
你想我再付一百万消灭他?
Are you suggesting I invest another million to remove him?
那要看你了
That's up to you .
我想想吧
I will give it some thought.
既然你来了
Since you have chosen to meet me,
今晚来吃晚饭吧
perhaps you will dine here tonight.
荣幸之至
I'll be deIighted .
那么九点整
9: 00 then .
凌波 送他走
Ling Po, see this gentleman out.
别告诉我你见到他
Don't tell me you saw him .
他甚至邀请我吃晚饭
He even invited me to dinner.
他必定发觉我使他心痒痒
He must have found me quite titillating .
到时
In due time, I shall be laid to rest here
在这充实、愉快 漫长的一生过后
in my mausoleum
我就会躺在我的钞墓内安息
after a useful , happy, long life.
我不会让邦德缩短它的
And I do not intend to allow Mr. Bond to shorten it.
我去开车
I'll get the car.
我宁愿跟你一起吃晚饭
Goodnight, you know I'd much rather have dinner with you .
我明白的 请你快回来
Oh , I understand , James. Please hurry back.
我尽快致电你
I'll ring as soon as I do.
也许吃夜宵吧
A midnight snack might be just the thing .
我会把酒保持冰冻
I'll keep the wine properly chilled .
其余的都要暖暖的吧
And everything else warm , I trust.
- 再见 - 再见
- Bye-bye. - Bye-bye.
其余的都要暖暖的吧?
"And everything else warm?"
希望你不介意 送我两个侄女一程
I hope you don't mind giving my nieces a lift.
晚安
Good evening .
海发正在途中
Hai Fat's is on the way.
我放下她们后 再回这里守候着
I'll drop the girls, come back here and hang around .
- 再见 - 再见
- Bye-bye. - Bye-bye.
我是斯卡曼加
The name's Scaramanga.
海发先生约了我
Mr. Fat is expecting me.
"恐怖乐园"
"Grislyland ."
晚安
A pleasant evening .
抓他! 快点!
Get him . Come on .
停手!
Stop it.
别在这里乱来
Not here.
这是我的家
This is my home.
带邦德先生到学校去
Take Mr. Bond to school .
真舒服
Heaven .
舒服死了
Definitely heaven .
塔希曼
Tashman .
Chula.
Chula ! Chula ! Chula !
你没事吗?
Are you all right?
你怎么知道我在此?
How did you find me?
这地方是海发的
Hai Fat owns this place.
你们退后
Stand back, girls.
忘记告诉你
Forgot to tell you .
她们的父亲经营空手道学校的
Their father runs a karate school .
坐稳!
Hang on !
各位 这可算是一团糟
What you might call a Mexican screw off, gentlemen .
漂亮的小姐 一百铢
Pretty lady. 100 baht.
八十铢
No, no. 80 baht.
五十铢 漂亮的小姐
50 baht, pretty lady.
是真的大象 五十铢
Real elephant. 50 baht.
大象 很便宜的 先生 一百铢
Elephant. Bargain , mister. 100 baht.
大象 是真的
Elephant. Real elephant.
五十铢
50 baht.
你很帅 四十铢
You are very handsome man . 40 baht.
给你个特价 二十铢
For you , mister, 20 baht.
若你能使东西开快些
I'll tell you what, sonny, I'll give you 20, 000 baht
我就给你二万铢
if you can make this heap go any faster.
二万铢!
20, 000 baht.
恐怕我要欠你了
I'm afraid I'll have to owe you .
死游客! 二万铢!
Bloody tourist! 20, 000 baht!
岂有此理 你这污水猪!
Goddamn little brown water hog !
什么事 JW?
Oh , what's the matter, J.W., hon?
你试在我的地方这样做
You just try that in my bayou , boy!
我连你的屁股也扯掉!
I'd haul your ass !
JW 看!
Oh , look, J.W.
我想买一只那些可爱小象
I just gotta have me one of those cute little elephants.
象!
Elephant?
我们是支持民主党的!
We're Democrats, Maybelle.
你叫那些尖头怪脱下睡衣
If you got your little pointy heads out of them pajamas,
你就不会迟到上班!
you wouldn't be late for work!
我早已料到!
J .W. : I knew it!
你们这些尖头怪
You pointy-heads has no more idea
比信天翁的交通控制概念
of traffic control
还要差!
than a goony bird !
别将你的鼻子 伸进我的裤子里 听到吗?
Get your cotton-picking schnoz out of my pants. Hear, now?
你真丑
Boy. You is ugly.
JW啊?
J.W.?
你在哪里?
Where are you?
他们在那学校教什么?
What do they teach in that school?
芭蕾舞?
Ballet dancing?
我不觉得让邦德逃走很好笑
I find nothing remotely amusing about Mr. Bond's escape.
你低估他了
You underestimated him .
即使我的影响力
Even my influence doesn't extend
也伸展不到英国特工处
into the British Secret Service.
我应该低调
I shall lie low, too.
我不会搞坏
I don't intend to jeopardize the project
我投资了一半财产
in which I've invested half my fortune
并会赚数十亿的计划
when it's ready to yieId billions.
你会在哪里躲藏?
Where will you hide out?
这跟你无关
That does not concern you .
这个拿去
Take this.
把他还给厂房
Return it to the plant
没我的准许别离开
and don't leave there without my permission .
提醒你 你是替我工作的
May I remind you that you work for me.
我雇用你做初级合伙人
I took you on as a junior partner
只是偶尔可以被利用一下罢了 没什么了
to be an occasional convenience, nothing more.
我不是聘用你来管我的事的
I did not hire you to interfere in my affairs.
清楚明白吗?
Is that clearly understood?
非常清楚
Yes. Very clearly.
我甚至开始后悔考虑聘请你
I now regret having even considered employing your services.
不过先别说这个问题
But that is beside the point.
邦德不知道你在曼谷
Bond doesn't know you're in Bangkok.
他从没见过你 但他认识我
He's never seen you . But he knows me.
这就是问题所在
That's the problem .
这不是问题
That's no problem .
发生什么事?
What happened?
海发先生刚刚辞职
Mr. Fat has just resigned .
我现在是新董事主席
I'm the new chairman of the board .
他一向都喜欢那个钞墓
He always did like that mausoleum .
把他埋在那里
Put him in it.
对不起 都是赫副官
Sorry about that, darling . It was Hip.
没海发的影踪
There's still no sign of Hai Fat.
所有查询都受到东方式的婉拒
Every inquiry gets a polite Oriental brush-off.
敬赠的
With compliments.
"培约"?
"Phuyuck"?
是1974年的
'74, sir.
我喜欢
I approve.
真的?
You do?
不是指酒
Oh , not the wine.
是你的连衣裙
Your frock.
适当的位置紧身
Tight in all the right places.
钮扣不太多
Not too many buttons.
东南亚的标准制服
Standard uniform for Southeast Asia.
钮扣在后面
The buttons are down the back.
一定是由"Q"设计的
Designed by Q, no doubt.
其中一颗定是自杀药丸
One of them's a suicide pill , I suppose?
不 那钮扣内置自动引导装置
No, but the bottom one has a homer in it.
真有原创力
How original .
干杯
A toast.
为这一刻
To this moment
和为将来的时刻
and the moment yet to come.
在我们这行业 恐怕
In our profession , I'm afraid ,
无法指望那一刻来临
you never can count on that moment to come.
天晓得明年这个时候 你与我在何方
Who knows where you and I will be this time next year?
大概是天各一方吧
Opposite sides of the worId , most likely.
相距太远了
That's too far apart.
如果赫副官找不到线索
Now, if Hip doesn't come up with a lead ,
今晚我们就没有什么要办
there's really nothing very much for us to do tonight.
或者有呢?
Or is there?
你使我心痒痒
Oh , darling , I'm tempted .
但我没兴趣花几个小时
But killing a few hours as one of your passing fancies
来打发你的幻想
isn't quite my scene.
培约
"Phuyuck."
晚安 真叫人意外
Ah . Goodnight, what a pleasant surprise.
我那"难以得手"的表现 很短促吧
My hard-to-get act didn't last very long , did it?
我受过训练应付特如其来的事
I was trained to expect the unexpected ,
但他们没有教我应付 你穿着睡衣的情况
but they never prepared me for anything like you in a nightie.
我还以为这件事永不会发生
James, I thought this wouId never happen .
什么使你改变主意?
What made you change your mind?
我意志薄弱
I'm weak.
别动!
Don't move.
安黛拉小姐
Miss Anders.
你穿上衣服我认不出你
I didn't recognize you with your cIothes on .
我收买侍者让我进来的
I bribed the bellboy to let me in .
我想来警告你
I've come to warn you .
你有危险
You're in great danger.
我经常都是的
I usually am .
所以我用三个枕头的旧把戏
That's why I use the old three-pillow trick.
请相信我 我冒险到来的
Please believe me. I'm risking my life to come here.
你在乎我的安危令人感动
Well , your concern for my well-being is touching
也使我迷惑
but puzzles me.
斯卡曼加身在曼谷
Scaramanga is in Bangkok.
他也曾在香港 不过不是追杀我
He was in Hong Kong , too, but not after me.
我们说过了
We've been through that routine.
他是猛兽 我讨厌他
He's a monster. I hate him .
那么离开他
Then leave him .
你不能对斯卡曼加一走了之
You don't walk out on Scaramanga.
他一定会找到我的
There's no place he wouldn't find me.
你需要一个好律师
You need a good lawyer.
我需要007
I need 007.
你以为谁把刻上你号码的
Who do you think sent that bullet
子弹寄去伦敦?
to London with your number on it?
是我
I did .
把他的指纹印在 那纸条上很不容易
And it wasn't easy getting his fingerprint on the note.
原谅我理解力迟钝
You'll forgive me if I've been a little slow on the uptake.
你不明白你是世上 唯一可把他杀死的人吗?
Don't you see you're the only man in the world who can kill him?
为何你有那个想法?
What gives you that idea?
斯卡曼加对你的观感
The way Scaramanga speaks about you .
他甚至蛮喜欢你
Even has a likeness of you .
真是过奖
I'm flattered .
我想他死
I want him dead .
给我一个价钱 什么都可以 我会付给你
Name your price. Anything . I'll pay it.
若你喜欢 你也可得到我
You can have me, too, if you Iike.
我也蛮有吸引力
I'm not unattractive.
起码 你开始说出真相了
At last you're starting to tell the truth .
我梦想你释放我
I've dreamed about you setting me free.
我一直梦想 那个太阳能感应震动器
I've been dreaming about a solex agitator.
有听过吗?
Ever heard of one?
或者你也可得到它
Perhaps you can have that, too.
不 我的衣服在里面
No, my clothes are in there.
- 我要宰掉那女人!  - 晚一点吧
- I'll kill that woman . - Later.
很迷人
Charming .
寄出那子弹是个妙计
It was an inspiration sending that bullet.
你晚了
You're late.
那是两片连映
It was a double feature.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
放好手饰
Putting my jewelry away.
你可以出来了
You can come out now.
现在几点?
What time is it?
两点
2: 00-ish .
两点?
2: 00?
我躲在这里两个小时?
Do you mean I've been in here for two hours?
这都是职责的一部分
All in the line of duty.
职责! 我明早辞职了!
Duty? I'm resigning in the morning .
别让我们失望
Oh , Goodnight, come on , don't let us down .
特工处需要像你这样的女人
The Service needs women like you .
但很明显你不需要
Well , obviously you don't.
原谅我吧 亲爱的
Forgive me, darling .
我答应你会轮到你的
Your turn will come, I promise.
只要她把那仪器带来给我
As soon as she brings me that solex.
为杀斯卡曼加?
For killing Scaramanga?
如果她首先替我拿到 太阳能感应震动器
If she gets me the solex agitator first.
首先?
First?
詹姆斯 别乱来
James, you must be good .
嗯
Hmm .
到我下次见到她时就会知道
We'll find out about that the next time I meet her.
她已在安排了
She's making the arrangements.
抱歉我迟到
Sorry I'm Iate.
曼谷的交通很糟
Bangkok traffic's worse than Piccadilly.
他已经联络过
He's made contact.
那个帅哥好吗?
How's the charm boy doing?
还用你问?
Need you ask?
在外面见
Meet you outside.
有把它带来吗?
Did you bring it?
我把它留在你手提包内
Darling , I left it in your handbag .
一定在里面的
It must be in here somewhere, dear.
我见到店内那男人给了你
I saw the man in the shop give it to you .
没有那张票 我们不能在海关拿到收据
Without the ticket, we can't get a receipt for customs.
你找不到的了 我在你来之前已看过
You won't find it in there, Mr. Bond . I looked before you came.
我也不会那样做
I wouldn't do that either.
看看你背后
Look behind you .
低一点
Lower.
花生袋里的手枪 真有创意
A gun and a bag of peanuts. How original .
下一步呢?
What will they think of next?
我叫做斯卡曼加
My name is Scaramanga.
弗朗斯科斯卡曼加
Francisco Scaramanga.
我觉得是认识你的
I feel I know you ,
虽然我从没想过我们会见面
although I never thought we should ever really meet.
这真是我的荣幸 邦德先生
It's a very great pleasure for me, Mr. Bond ,
全赖安黛拉小姐
thanks to Miss Anders.
你表示感激的方法真特别
You've a strange way of showing your gratitude.
一妇不能侍二主
A mistress cannot serve two masters.
痛心的一枪 但十分感激
A difficult shot, but most gratifying .
我们都各自玩得痛快
Well , we all get our jollies one way or another.
我的喜好一直是枪
Mine have always been guns, Mr. Bond .
我儿时在马戏团中长大
When I was a boy, I was brought up in a circus.
我唯一的朋友是一只非洲大象
My only real friend was a magnificent African bull elephant.
有一天他的训练员虐待他 他发狂
One day his handler mistreated him and he went berserk.
流血 将要死时
Bleeding , dying ,
他来找我
he came and found me.
单脚站立 这是他的绝招
Stood on one leg , his best trick,
他把我提起放在他背上
picked me up and put me on his back.
那家伙用枪射他的眼睛
The man emptied the gun into his eye.
我用我的手枪向他还以颜色
I emptied my stage pistol into his.
以眼还眼
An eye for an eye.
花生?
Nut?
邦德先生 我一直以为自己喜欢动物
You see, Mr. Bond , I always thought I liked animals
后来我发现我更喜欢杀人
and I discovered that I liked killing people even more.
保管它 无论如何别掉了
Keep this. Whatever you do, don't lose it.
我要回去帮詹姆斯
I have to get back to help James.
出了状况吗?
Something's gone wrong?
有个侏儒用枪指着他
There's a midget with a gun on him .
侏儒?
A midget?
是我在露臀夜总会外见到的那个
Same one I saw outside the Bottoms Up.
那个女孩死了 通知警方
And the girl is dead . Call the poIice.
别管这个女孩 她可以被取代的
Forget the girl . She's repIaceable.
我会查看她偷了我什么
I shall find what she stole from me.
我对你没有敌意
Personally, I've got nothing against you , Mr. Bond ,
希望我们不会再有任何瓜葛
so let us hope our paths never cross again .
请别跟踪我
Please don't try to follow me.
你那个拿花生的朋友不会喜欢的
Your peanut-toting friend back there wouldn't like it.
没错
No, he wouldn't.
要试我的吗?
You want to try one of mine?
- 那太阳能感应器呢?  - 给了晚安
- Where's the solex? - I gave it to Goodnight.
- 那么她在哪?  - 在外面
- And where's Goodnight? - Outside.
她一定是在车旁
She must be by the car.
女人啊 给我通话器
Women . Walkie-talkie.
晚安 你在哪里?
Goodnight, where are you?
我被锁在行李厢
Somebody locked me in a boot.
什么?
In a what?
我被锁在那侏儒的车内
The midget's car. I'm locked in.
车子是古铜色的 车顶黑色 车牌7543
It's a bronze car with a black roof, number 7543.
- 车钥匙!  - 我没有
- The keys. - I haven't got them .
糟了
Oh , no.
晚安 车钥匙呢?
Goodnight, where are the car keys?
在我手上 那太阳能感应器也在我手上
I've got the keys. And I've got the solex, too.
计程车!
Taxi !
你别逃 我们看到你了
Stay in there, Goodnight. We've got you spotted .
计程车 快!
HIP: Taxi ! Taxi !
可以示范一下吗?
How about a demonstration , boy?
没问题
Certainly, sir.
究竟发生什么事?
What the hell is going on?
我知道你是谁!
Now I know you !
天
Oh , no.
你是那情报员!
You're that secret agent.
来自英国特工处的!
That English secret agent from England .
你在追着某人
You're chasing somebody.
这次要追谁? 共产党员?
Who you after this time, boy? Commies?
去抓他们!
Let's go get them .
我全力支持你
I'm with you all the way.
似乎有麻烦
Uh-oh ! I think we've got trouble.
停下你们的车 你们这些黄种尖头怪!
Pull your cars over, you little brown pointy-heads !
我是警察!
I'm a peace officer!
你还在吗? 詹姆斯?
James, are you still there? James?
你听到吗? 詹姆斯?
Can you hear me? James !
好 别怕
All right, Goodnight. Don't panic.
那是谁?  是…
Who's that? It's. . .
- 是总部 - 让我跟他们说
- It's headquarters. - Let me talk to them .
你好 我是路易斯安那州 警察局的佩帕警长
Hello. This is Sheriff J .W. Pepper, Louisiana State Police.
告诉我那身在纳里饭店的妻子
Now, you call my wife at the Narai Hotel
我有任务在身
and tell her I'm on a mission.
我被委任做代表
I've been deputized .
对吗?  对
Right? Right.
我们要追哪辆车?
Which car are we all chasing , boy?
让开! 
Move it! Move it!
把那堆废铁驶离马路!
Get that piece of junk off the road !
他们去了左边
They went to the left, boy.
加油吧
Press that pedal , boy.
他们到底去了哪里?
Where the hell they got to?
你出错了 小子
You goofed , boy.
最近的桥在两里后
Nearest bridge is two miles back.
该死! 你在?
J .W. : God damn ! What the. . .
什么事? 你想做什么?
What's going on? What the hell you doing now, boy?
桥在那边!
The bridge is that way!
你不会是想…
You're not thinking of. . .
没错
I sure am , boy.
有听过亡命特技人吗?
Ever heard of Evel Knievel?
我从没试过这样做
I never done that before !
其实我也没试过
Well , neither have I , actually.
去对付他们!
Let's go get them , boy!
你不要管 这是我的部门
You stay put, boy. This is my department.
你们有这能耐真好!
Glad to see you boys are on the ball .
我是路易斯安那州 警察局的佩帕警长
Sheriff J .W. Pepper, Louisiana State Police.
这是我的身份证明 
Here's my identification .
执法联会 美国
This is the Law Enforcement Association , American Legion .
我与我的搭挡在执行秘密任务
Me and my partner here, we're on a secret mission .
你在干什么?
Hey! What the hell you doing?
把钱包还给我
Hey! Give me my wallet back.
开门
Doors.
你不可以这么做!
J .W. : You can't do this to me !
把钱包还给我!
I want my wallet back!
解开这手铐
Take these goddamn bracelets off!
我要告你们错误拘捕 警察施暴
I'm gonna sue ya for false arrest, police brutality!
我有熟人的! 我叫联邦调查局 和中情局教训你们
I got connections ! I'm gonna get the FBI on your ass, the CIA.
岂有此理 我要找季辛吉!
God damn it, I'm gonna get Henry Kissinger!
看着我 我在跟你讲话
Look at me when I'm talking to ya, boy!
什么?
What's the matter?
你们这些尖头怪从没见过飞机吗?
Ain't none of you pointy-heads ever seen an airplane before?
詹姆斯 你还在吗?
James? James, are you still there?
听到吗? 我想车已经停下来了
Can you hear me? I think we've stopped.
要报告的就是这么多
That is really all there is to report, sir.
若我没听错 斯卡曼加已经逃走
So, if I heard correctly, Scaramanga got away.
对
Yes, sir.
搭一辆长了翅膀的汽车
In a car that sprouted wings.
那绝对可行
That's perfectly feasible, sir.
我们也正在研究这样的车
As a matter of fact, we're working on one now.
Q 住嘴
Oh , Q, shut up.
- 晚安在行李厢 - 没错
- And Miss Goodnight was in the boot. - Yes, sir.
那辆飞机汽车被扔弃在
We found the car-plane abandoned
曼谷以西二百里的地方
about 200 miles west of Bangkok.
- 那太阳能感应器呢?  - 在晚安的手袋内
- And the solex? - In Goodnight's handbag , sir.
那晚安现在在哪?
Where is Goodnight now?
我们也不知道
We don't know, sir.
通讯系统接收不到
Communications aren't picking up the signal
引导装置的讯号
from the homer she has, supplied by Q.
废话! 他们只是没把
Rubbish! They're simply not stepping up...
接收率提高
the reception sufficiently to enable.
Q 住嘴
Oh , shut up, Q.
真是混乱无能的运作!
Of all the fouled-up, half-witted operations.
有什么事?
M: What do you want?
我们接收到晚安的讯号
We've picked up Goodnight's signal , sir.
有消息了
Well , that's something .
不过有些颇奇怪的事
But there is something rather curious, sir.
我们在这儿
Our sector's here
而她的讯号
and we're receiving her signal from somewhere
来自这里离岸的某地方
off this coastline off shore here.
这一张是较大的比例
Now, here it is on a much larger scale.
她就在
That's where she is.
这群小岛里
In this group of small islands.
这就是我们需要的 中国共产党水域
M: That's all we need , Red Chinese waters.
我们可以当疏忽迷路闯了进去
Well , we could stray inadvertently into them , sir.
我可以飞在他们雷达 侦测范围以下
I could fly low under their radar screen .
绝对没问题
Absolutely out of the question .
如果首相知道
If the PM gets to hear of this,
他会把我吊死的
he'll hang me from the yardarm .
正式来说 你什么也不知道
Officially, you won't know a thing about it, sir.
有一架小型海上飞机飞近你的岛
There's a small seaplane approaching your island .
要我们采取行动吗?
Do you want us to take any action?
不用 请什么也不要做
No. No, please don't do anything .
是的 是一个我等着来的客人
Yes, it's a guest I'm expecting .
不 他不会离开
No, he won't be leaving .
我是尼拿克
I am Nick Nack.
我比较喜欢1962年的
I prefer the '62 myself.
不过总比一包花生味道要好
Still , beats a bag of peanuts.
斯卡曼加先生会亲自欢迎你
Monsieur Scaramanga will welcome you personally.
对不起 邦德先生
Forgive me, Mr. Bond .
表现很不得体 但我无法抗拒
A vulgar display, but I couldn't resist it
因为再见到你太高兴了
because I am so delighted to see you again .
没杀伤力的玩具
A harmless toy.
你可以看到 我是完全没有携械的
I am , as you can see now, completeIy unarmed .
香烟?
Cigarette?
我们有许多相同之处
We have so much in common , Mr. Bond .
我们有很多事讨论
We have so much to discuss,
将来不再有这个机会
and we will never have this opportunity again .
我们的职业是最孤独的
Ours is the loneliest profession ,
让我们共聚数小时吧
so let us spend a few pleasant hours together.
我如何能拒绝这样殷勤的邀请?
How can I refuse such a gracious invitation?
太好了! 
Splendid . Splendid !
尼拿克 我期望你有超水准表现
Nick Nack, I expect you to surpass yourself.
他是一流名厨
He's a Cordon Bleu , you know.
是了 晚安小姐在哪里?
By the way, where's Miss Goodnight?
她在这儿附近
Oh , she's around here somewhere.
她没办法离开的
There's no way for her to leave,
所以是行动自如的
so she does as she pleases.
喜欢我的岛吗?
How do you like my island?
有点偏僻 不是吗?
A bit off the beaten track, isn't it?
是免费出租的 我偶尔给我的房东些恩惠
It's rent-free. I do my landlords an occasional favor.
很布置的安排
A cozy arrangement.
聘请佣人麻烦吧
Servant problem , I suppose.
也不是
Not at all .
尼拿克很称职
Nick Nack does for me very nicely.
通常只有我俩
Usually there's just the two of us,
不过客人到来也很方便
but having guests is no inconvenience.
我们自给自足
We're entirely self-supporting .
所有你能想到的
We have every electrical laborsaving device
省电的装置都有
you could possibIy think of.
这是一间密封室
This is an air lock, as you are doubtless aware.
当然是自动化的
Automatic, of course.
其实 我们这里有充足电力
Naturally, we have an ample supply of electricity here.
让我给你看
Let me show you .
这里应该可以供电 给几只电动牙刷
This should run a few electric toothbrushes.
请上去
Up here.
这儿就是太阳能源站
A solar energy station .
这就是关于它的一切
So this is what it's all about.
热电发电机
Thermoelectric generators to convert
将太阳能转化为电力
solar energy into electricity.
当然是由海发建筑公司建造的
All built by Hai Fat's construction company, no doubt.
我继承了他的企业
Somehow I seem to have inherited it from him .
是全自动的
It's all fully automated .
他是克拉 看管一切
That's Kra, maintenance and security.
若尼拿克不是在擦亮银器时
He looks after everything in here.
就会做其余的事
Nick Nack does everything else when he isn't polishing the silver.
他们说电力储藏在附近
They tell me the electricity is stored in here somewhere.
科学站始终不是我的长处
Science was never my strong point.
超导电线圈 被液化氦冷却
Superconductivity coils cooled by liquid helium .
若我是你就不会
If I were you , I wouldn't stick my finger,
把手指插进去
or anything else for that matter, in there.
在零下453度
At 453 degrees below zero,
液体氦气 会像折冰柱般折断它
that liquid helium would break it off like an icicle.
你果然比我知道多许多
You really know far more about it than I do, Mr. Bond .
我在请求每个国家
I'm arranging for every country that can afford the price
派专家到来
to send their experts here to see for themselves.
但要直到收到钱 才有那太阳能感应器 对吗?
But no solex until the money is in the bank. Right?
没错
Right.
我经历过类似的情况
I have run across similar situations.
没有像我这里的吧
Not what I've got here.
最高竞投者可兴建
This way the highest bidder can build
数百个站
hundreds of these stations
再出售数百个特许经营权
and sell franchises for hundreds more.
他会赚得荷包满满的
He will literally have the sun in his pocket.
太阳能的独家经营
A monopoly on solar power.
石油酋长会收买你 以防止你把太阳能推出市场
The oil sheiks will pay you just to keep solar energy off the market.
我也这样想过
The thought had occurred to me.
这是收集的地方
This is the collection point.
就是它被放置的地方
Ah . So that's where it belongs.
在热交换器的太阳能感应器
Our famous solex in the still down there
把热力输送到发热器
transmits heat to the thermal generators.
透过这个收集的?
It's collected through this?
不过从何收集?
But where is it collected from?
你需要太阳
You need the sun .
看着那蘑菇型的石头
Watch that mushroom-shaped rock.
很巧妙 不是吗?
Ingenious, isn't it?
把面板锁定太阳的位置 然后它自动追踪
The panels lock on to the sun and then track it automatically.
类似这样吧
Something like that, yes.
啊
Ah .
那些面板必须要制造
Reflected through this, those panels must produce a heat
至少华氏3500度的热力
of at least 3,500 degrees Fahrenheit.
可以这样说 邦德先生
If you say so, Mr. Bond .
我们可在任何地方把能源集中
But I do know that we can focus the power wherever we want.
过来这边 我给你看
Over here. I'll show you .
这是额外的
This is a bonus.
连太阳能感应器一起发售 不另收费
Goes with the solex. No extra charge.
我最喜欢这部分
This is the part I really like.
这就是我所称的太阳能
Now, that's what I call solar power.
我称这做麻烦
That's what I call trouble.
你得承认 我是不折不扣的
You must admit, Mr. Bond , I am now undeniably
金枪人
the Man with the Golden Gun .
午餐时候到了
Ah . Lunch .
请到这边来
This way, Mr. Bond .
晚安小姐
Ah ! Miss Goodnight.
詹姆斯
James !
我们不是穿得太讲究吗?
Aren't we a little overdressed , Goodnight?
我喜欢女孩穿比基尼
I like a girl in a bikini .
不会隐藏武器
No concealed weapons.
晚安小姐 请坐 邦德先生
Miss Goodnight, please. Mr. Bond .
看看尼拿克为我们准备了什么
Now let's see what Nick Nack has for us.
是蘑菇
Ah . Mushrooms.
炒蘑菇似乎很有趣
The fried mushroom looks terribly interesting .
我也留意到 我晚点再吃
Yes, I noticed that. I'll get around to it later.
太阳下好玩吗?
Having fun in the sun , Goodnight?
好玩
Yes.
我可以永远留在这里
I could stay here forever.
嗯!
Hmm !
了不起
Excellent.
有点像1934年的慕东
Slightly reminiscent of a '34 Mouton .
那我一定要把它加在酒窖里
Then I must add it to my cellar.
你的生活真写意
You live well , Scaramanga.
每次交易都得一百万 这让我负担得起
At a million dollars a contract, I can afford to, Mr. Bond .
你为一小点金钱工作
You work for peanuts.
只获得英女皇一句由衷的赞赏
A hearty "well done" from Her Majesty the Queen
和少量的退休金
and a pittance of a pension .
除此之外我们都是一样的
Apart from that, we are the same.
为我们干一杯
To us, Mr. Bond .
我们是最出色的
We are the best.
有个很有用的形容词
There's a useful four-letter word ,
形容你很贴切
and you're full of it.
我杀人时 都是按政府给我的命令
When I kill , it's on the specific orders of my government.
而我杀的都是杀手
And those I kill are themselves killers.
邦德先生
Oh , come, come, Mr. Bond .
我对你很失望
You disappoint me.
承认你杀人时
You get as much fulfillment out of killing as I do,
如我一样很有满足感吧
so why don't you admit it?
我承认杀你会很满足
I admit killing you would be a pleasure.
你最初见到我时就应杀掉我
You should've done that when you first saw me.
英国人不认为
But then of course the English don't consider it
冷血杀人有风度
sporting to kill in cold blood , do they?
别指望这样
Don't count on that.
我可在你登陆时射杀你
I could've shot you down when you landed
那是最不费劲的
but that would've been ridiculously easy.
就像每个伟大的艺术家
You see, Mr. Bond , like every great artist,
我想在人生中
I want to create an indisputable
创一次丰功伟绩
masterpiece once in my Iifetime.
007之死
The death of 007,
面对面
face to face,
胜利将属于我
will be mine.
你指装饰和展览 你这个石制壁炉架?
You mean , stuffed and displayed over your rocky mantelpiece?
这个主意很有趣 但我是以历史作考虑
That's an amusing idea, but I was thinking in terms of history.
两个巨人的决斗
A duel between titans.
我的金枪对你的沃尔达PPK
My golden gun against your Walther PPK.
大家机会均等
Each of us with a 50-50 chance.
我六颗子弹对你一颗?
Six bullets to your one?
我只需要一颗
I only need one.
听来有点老套吧 是吗?
Sounds a bit oId-fashioned , doesn't it?
我意思是 黎明时份决斗的那种事
I mean , pistols at dawn , that sort of thing .
的确是
Indeed , it is, Mr. Bond ,
不过这仍是男子汉的最好考验
but it still remains the only true test for gentlemen .
恐怕你没资格取得胜利
I doubt if you qualify on that score.
不过我接受你挑战
However, I accept.
等我先吃掉尼拿克
As soon as I finish this delicious lunch
为我们弄的美味午餐
that Nick Nack has prepared for us.
两位 让我提醒你们 这是生死决战
Messieurs, I will remind you this is un duella mort.
只有其中一人可离开
Only one of you can leave the fieId of honor.
如果需要最后一枪
If a coup de grce is necessary,
作为裁判的我会亲自操刀
as your referee, I will administer it myself.
我预料没有损伤 要干净利落的一死
I do not expect wounds. Only a clean kill.
在我指挥下
On my command
双方要退后二十步
each contestant will take 20 paces.
准备好了吗?  斯卡曼加先生
Are you ready, Monsieur Scaramanga?
准备好了
Ready.
准备好了吗 邦德先生?
Are you ready, Monsieur Bond?
准备好了
Ready.
我开始数了
I will now begin the count.
一 二 三 四 五
1 , 2, 3, 4, 5,
六 七 八 九
6, 7, 8, 9,
十 十一 十二 十三
10, 11 , 12, 13,
十四 十五 十六
14, 15, 16,
十七 十八 十九 二十!
17, 18, 19, 20 !
如果你杀了他
If you kill him ,
这里一切都是我的
all this be mine.
邦德先生 到这边来
This way, Monsieur Bond .
射得好
Monsieur, good shooting .
我从没杀过侏儒
I've never killed a midget before,
不过凡事总有第一次
but there can always be a first time.
先生!
Oh, monsieur.
你只剩下三颗子弹
You only have three bullets left!
我耍你的!
I fooled you.
- 晚安 - 詹姆斯!
- Goodnight. - James !
詹姆斯
James.
镇定点
Steady, Goodnight.
他在哪里?
Where is he?
毙命在最后一击下
Flat on his coup de grce.
快离开这鬼地方 和找出那个太阳能感应器
Come on . Let's get out of this fun palace and find that solex.
你留下
Wait here.
我去对付那维修工人
I'll take care of the maintenance man .
我已经搞定了
I already did .
让他冷僵了
I laid him out cold .
- 你?  - 对
- You did? - Yes.
你真的不如外表看来那么简单
There's more to you than meets the eye, Goodnight.
我不想问愚蠢的问题
Goodnight, I hate to ask stupid questions,
但究竟你是在哪里弄死他?
but where exactly did you knock him cold?
他掉在那个池内
He landed in that one.
你不信告示的吗?
Don't you believe in signs?
在他的体温 让氦气提升到零度以上之前
We've got about five minutes before his
我们还剩下大约五分钟
body temperature raises that helium well above zero.
接着这整个地方就会爆炸!
Then this whole damn place will go sky high .
对不起! 我不知道
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
关掉那道光!
Kill the beam !
按撤销主按钮!
Hit the master override switch !
什么?
The what?
晚安?
Goodnight?
我在
Yes, James.
留心听着
Now, listen carefully.
上面有个操纵台
There's a console up there.
必定有一个扫描连锁按钮的
Now, there must be a scanner interlock button on it.
按它
Push it!
你还在吗?
Goodnight, are you still there?
那应该在辅助反馈电路上
It'll be on the auxiliary feedback circuit.
"电脑连锁"是这个吗?
Computer interlock. Is that it?
把每个都按下 好吗?
Just push every damn button , will you?
晚安 做得好
Good girl , Goodnight. You've done it.
我做到了?
Oh , I have?
快离开 我拿到了!
Goodnight, get the hell out of there ! I've got it!
真希望你会游泳
I hope you can swim , Goodnight.
这边!
This way.
他的中式帆船就停在转角处
His junk is moored around the corner.
是谁掌舵的?
But, darling , who is at the wheel?
- 乔治 - 乔治?
- George. - George?
自动船长
Automatic pilot.
我们应在八小时内 抵达香港
We should make Hong Kong in about eight hours.
出入不会太大
Give or take a littIe.
我一直都想从中国乘一艘慢船
I always wanted to take a slow boat from China.
我要杀死你
I'll kill you .
我要杀死你!
I'll kill you !
你竟然
Why, you . . .
等等! 等一下!
Wait! Just wait!
你个王八蛋
Son of a bitch ! Ow!
嘿 你在干嘛呢?  快点进去
Hey! Hey, what are you doing? Get in there.
哦!
Ouch !
我无法呼吸!
Come on ! I can't breathe !
喔!
Ow!
你会后悔的!
You'll be sorry!
我虽然矮小 但我的记性很好!
I may be small , but I never forget!
不放我出来我就杀掉你
I'll kill you if you don't let me out of here ! Ow!
放我出来! 你这大坏蛋!
Let me out, you big bully!
住口
Shut up.
你怎样处置他?
What did you do with him?
你认为呢?
What do you think?
詹姆斯 不是吧!
Oh , James, you didn't.
我就是那样做
Yes, I damn well did .
相信你已把玻璃清理好吧
Got all the glass out of the bed , I trust.
我们不想有别的东西妨碍我们 是吗?
We don't want anything else to disturb our peace, do we?
现在 刚才到哪了?
Now, where were we?
喔 詹姆斯
Oh , James.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
有事发生
Something came up.
找谁?
Hello?
找到你了 邦德
Ah ! There you are, Bond .
做得好 恭喜你
Well done. Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you , sir.
晚安小姐在吗? 我想跟她谈谈
Is Miss Goodnight with you? I'd like a word with her.
等等
Hold on , sir.
邦德? 你在吗?
Bond? Bond, are you there?
晚安?
Goodnight?
她快来了
She's just coming , sir.
晚安?
Goodnight?
- 晚安 - 晚安
- Goodnight. - Good night, sir.